class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}
List<QuestionModel> farm_automation_and_robotics = [


QuestionModel(question: "1. What is the primary purpose of implementing robotics in agriculture?",
options: [
"A. Increase crop yield",
"B. Decrease labor costs",
"C. Improve efficiency",
"D. All of the above"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 3,
Solution: 'Robotics in agriculture aims to increase crop yield, decrease labor costs, and improve overall efficiency, making option D the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "2. Which type of robot is commonly used for precision farming tasks such as seeding and spraying?",
options: [
"A. Autonomous Ground Vehicles",
"B. Drones",
"C. Industrial Robots",
"D. Humanoid Robots"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 0,
Solution: 'Autonomous Ground Vehicles are commonly used in precision farming tasks like seeding and spraying, making option A the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "3. What is the role of sensors in farm automation?",
options: [
"A. Monitor crop health",
"B. Collect environmental data",
"C. Guide autonomous vehicles",
"D. All of the above"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 3,
Solution: 'Sensors in farm automation are used to monitor crop health, collect environmental data, and guide autonomous vehicles, making option D the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "4. How does the use of drones benefit agriculture?",
options: [
"A. Crop monitoring",
"B. Irrigation management",
"C. Pest control",
"D. All of the above"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 3,
Solution: 'Drones benefit agriculture by facilitating crop monitoring, irrigation management, and pest control, making option D the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "5. What is the purpose of computer vision in agricultural robotics?",
options: [
"A. Weed identification",
"B. Crop counting",
"C. Harvesting",
"D. All of the above"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 3,
Solution: 'Computer vision in agricultural robotics is used for tasks such as weed identification, crop counting, and harvesting, making option D the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "6. Which of the following is an example of a farm automation application in livestock management?",
options: [
"A. Automated feeding systems",
"B. Crop spraying drones",
"C. Harvesting robots",
"D. Weather monitoring"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 0,
Solution: 'Automated feeding systems are an example of farm automation in livestock management, making option A the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "7. What is the main advantage of using robotic milking systems in dairy farming?",
options: [
"A. Increased milk production",
"B. Reduced labor requirements",
"C. Improved milk quality",
"D. Enhanced cow comfort"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: 'Robotic milking systems in dairy farming offer the main advantage of reduced labor requirements, making option B the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "8. How does GPS technology contribute to precision agriculture?",
options: [
"A. Precision planting",
"B. Autonomous navigation",
"C. Crop monitoring",
"D. All of the above"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 3,
Solution: 'GPS technology contributes to precision agriculture by enabling precision planting, autonomous navigation, and crop monitoring, making option D the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "9. In the context of agricultural robotics, what does the term 'teleoperation' refer to?",
options: [
"A. Remote monitoring of crops",
"B. Remote control of robots",
"C. Automated irrigation",
"D. Satellite communication"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: "In agricultural robotics, 'teleoperation' refers to the remote control of robots, making option B the correct answer."
),

QuestionModel(question: "10. What is the purpose of variable rate technology (VRT) in precision agriculture?",
options: [
"A. Automated harvesting",
"B. Adjustable crop irrigation",
"C. Soil sampling",
"D. Autonomous plowing"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: 'Variable rate technology (VRT) in precision agriculture is used for adjustable crop irrigation, making option B the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "11. Which type of robot is designed for tasks such as fruit picking and sorting?",
options: [
"A. Industrial Robots",
"B. Humanoid Robots",
"C. Agricultural Robots",
"D. Telepresence Robots"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 2,
Solution: 'Agricultural robots are specifically designed for tasks such as fruit picking and sorting, making option C the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "12. How does automation contribute to sustainable agriculture practices?",
options: [
"A. Reduced environmental impact",
"B. Increased resource efficiency",
"C. Enhanced crop yield",
"D. All of the above"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 3,
Solution: 'Automation contributes to sustainable agriculture practices by reducing environmental impact, increasing resource efficiency, and enhancing crop yield, making option D the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "13. What is the primary purpose of automated irrigation systems in agriculture?",
options: [
"A. Water conservation",
"B. Pest control",
"C. Soil aeration",
"D. Seed planting"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 0,
Solution: 'The primary purpose of automated irrigation systems in agriculture is water conservation, making option A the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "14. How can robotics help in monitoring and managing crop diseases?",
options: [
"A. Early detection using sensors",
"B. Robotic spraying of pesticides",
"C. Automated harvesting",
"D. All of the above"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 3,
Solution: 'Robotics can help in monitoring and managing crop diseases through early detection using sensors, robotic spraying of pesticides, and automated harvesting, making option D the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "15. What is the significance of real-time data analytics in precision farming?",
options: [
"A. Predictive maintenance of robots",
"B. Timely decision-making",
"C. Crop yield optimization",
"D. All of the above"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 3,
Solution: 'Real-time data analytics in precision farming is significant for predictive maintenance of robots, timely decision-making, and crop yield optimization, making option D the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "16. Which technology is commonly used for autonomous navigation of agricultural robots in the field?",
options: [
"A. Lidar",
"B. RFID",
"C. Bluetooth",
"D. NFC"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 0,
Solution: 'Lidar technology is commonly used for autonomous navigation of agricultural robots in the field, making option A the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "17. What is the primary advantage of using AI in farm automation?",
options: [
"A. Improved decision-making",
"B. Reduced energy consumption",
"C. Faster data processing",
"D. Enhanced robotic agility"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 0,
Solution: 'The primary advantage of using AI in farm automation is improved decision-making, making option A the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "18. How can robotic systems contribute to sustainable pest management in agriculture?",
options: [
"A. Precision application of pesticides",
"B. Biological pest control",
"C. Automated pest monitoring",
"D. All of the above"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 3,
Solution: 'Robotic systems contribute to sustainable pest management in agriculture through precision application of pesticides, biological pest control, and automated pest monitoring, making option D the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "19. What role do actuators play in agricultural robots?",
options: [
"A. Collecting environmental data",
"B. Providing motion to robotic parts",
"C. Analyzing crop health",
"D. All of the above"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: 'Actuators in agricultural robots provide motion to robotic parts, making option B the correct answer.'
),

QuestionModel(question: "20. In the context of precision agriculture, what does the term 'geospatial technology' refer to?",
options: [
"A. Soil composition analysis",
"B. GPS-guided farming",
"C. Automated plowing",
"D. Weather forecasting"
],
correctAnswerIndex: 1,
Solution: "In precision agriculture, 'geospatial technology' refers to GPS-guided farming, making option B the correct answer."
),


];